WAI MONG (RAYMOND) KWAN

rayk199492@gmail.com raykayy.github.io/ +1 (416)-884-2950

in wai-mong-raymondkwan♠ RayKayy

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Aug. 2018 to Labs Nov. 2018

Diploma Full-Stack Javascript Web Development 2018

University of Aug. 2013 to Toronto Dec. 2017

H.B.A Environmental Management 2018

SUMMARY

An Environmental Management major who fell in love with coding after taking my first course in computer science towards the end of my degree.

I am a highly motivated and efficient individual with solid skills working with Javascript and the MERN stack, both independently and collaboratively; experience with multiple programming languages. I have planned, managed and developed web applications in a team-based environment. Works well in complex, dynamic, and deadline driven environments. Exceptional verbal and written communication skills, fluent in English, Mandarin, and Cantonese. Internationally experienced, flexible and

adaptive to varying environments both culturally and physically.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Javascript, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL

FRAMEWORK, LIBRARIES, ENVIRONMENTS: NodeJS, ReactJS, Express, JQuery, Knex

VCS, DATABASE SYSTEMS: PostgresSQL, MongoDB

LANGUAGES: English, Mandarin, Cantonese

EMPLOYMENT

ORACLE (CHINA) SOFTWARE SYSTEMS CO., LTD.

Marketing Intern

During my time as an intern at this company I:

Shanghai, China July 2015 to Aug. 2015

Sept. 2018 to Oct. 2018

- Increased efficiency of the company by translating multiple product information brochures from English to Chinese for coworkers, which are still in use today.
- Developed myself significantly as an individual regarding being a part of a team and as a member of the workforce.

PROJECTS

SINGLE PAGE APPLICATION: HICHAT

A single page real time chat app.

ReactJS, Web-sockets, Express, Webpack/Babel

Implemented stretch feature of parsing messages for image urls using RegEx;

auto scrolling of window on recipient of new messages;

unique username colour for each unique socket connection.

E-COMMERCE WEB APP: RAINFOREST

Implementation of features on an existing code base using the Ruby on Rails framework.

Rails: (ActiveRecord, ActionMailer, etc)

Picked up a new OOP language within a week (Ruby)

WEB APPLICATION: SMARTS

Sept. 2018 to Sept. 2018

Oct. 2018 to Oct. 2018

LHL midterm project: A smart todo list which sorts tasks based on one of five categories using multiple 'npm' packages and a trained model.

NodeJS, Express, JQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Natural.js, PostgresSQL, Knex.

Implemented the core middleware to connect our database and front-end by defining RESTful routes.

VOLUNTEERING

CHINESE UNDERGRADUATE ASSOCIATION UTM \cdot Media Associate University of Toronto

Helped with the production of media contents (Photoshop, Illustrator) for the promotion of events hosted by the association.